<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Red_Hat_JBoss_Developer_Studio_Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Set_up_Automatic_Runtime_Detection" remap="TID_13345">
	<sectioninfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>
				JBDS 7.0.0
			</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</sectioninfo>
	<title>Set up Automatic Runtime Detection</title>
	<para>
		JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio has automatic runtime detection for finding runtime servers. This can be set up to scan locations for runtime servers when a new workspace is created or the IDE starts.
	</para>
	<para>
		You may have already set this up during the installation process with the JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio installer. If you have not set this up or you installed JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio though Eclipse Marketplace, follow the procedure below to set up automatic runtime detection.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>Set up Automatic Runtime Detection</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>, expand <guilabel>JBoss Tools</guilabel> and select <guilabel>JBoss Tools Runtime Detection</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				To add a path for scanning, click <guibutton>Add</guibutton> and select a folder from which recursive scanning should commence. JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio scans this folder and any subfolders to check for new runtime servers.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If new runtime servers are found, you can create instances of them. Select the check boxes of the runtime servers you want to create and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>. If no runtime servers were found or you do not wish to create any instances click <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton>. In all cases, the path is added to the list of paths for scanning.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If you want this path to be scanned for runtime servers each time the IDE starts, select the <guilabel>Every start</guilabel> check box for the new path.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> to save any new paths and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Preferences</guilabel> window.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>