<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "JBoss_Tools_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Customizing Forge Tools</title>

	<section>
		<title>Customizing Overview</title>
	
		<para>The aim of this section is to guide you in customizing Forge Tools:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Customize when and how Forge starts</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Manage available Forge runtime servers</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Customize the Forge Start</title>
	
		<para>Forge Tools provides a number of customization options for starting Forge.</para>
	
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Start Forge on IDE start</term>
				<listitem><para>Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu> and select <guilabel>Forge</guilabel>. Select the <guilabel>Start Forge when workbench starts</guilabel> check box. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <application>Preferences</application> window.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Start Forge in debug mode</term>
				<listitem><para>The debug mode enables you to view the progress of processes executed on the Forge command line in the <guilabel>Debug</guilabel> tab. Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu> and select <guilabel>Forge</guilabel>. Select the <guilabel>Start Forge in Debug Mode</guilabel> check box. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <application>Preferences</application> window. This mode is most useful if you are developing plug-ins to extend the functionality of Forge.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Specify arguments for Forge start</term>
				<listitem><para>Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu> and select <guilabel>Forge</guilabel>. In the <guilabel>Forge Startup VM Arguments</guilabel> field, type the arguments you want Forge to use when it starts. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <application>Preferences</application> window.</para>
					<note><para>The standard Java VM arguments can be used when starting Forge. Additionally, Forge specific commands include <command>--debug</command> to start Forge in debug mode and <command>-pluginDir</command> to specify the directory where Forge should look for plug-ins to install rather than the default <filename>.forge/plugins</filename> directory.</para></note>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>	
	
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Manage Forge Runtime Servers</title>
	
		<para>Forge Tools is distributed with a Forge runtime server but you may want to use different versions of Forge runtime servers. Forge Tools provides the ability to manage the Forge runtime servers that are available in the IDE, as detailed below.</para>
		
		<para>To manage the available Forge runtime servers, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>, expand <guilabel>Forge</guilabel> and select <guilabel>Installed Forge Runtimes</guilabel>.
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para>To add a Forge runtime server, click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>. In the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> field, type a name to distinguish the Forge runtime server in the IDE. In the <guilabel>Location</guilabel> field, type the location of the runtime server or click <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to navigate to the location. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>To change the name or the location of a Forge runtime server, from the <guilabel>Installed Forge Runtimes</guilabel> list select a runtime and click <guibutton>Edit</guibutton>. Modify the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Location</guilabel> fields as appropriate. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>To delete a Forge runtime server, from the <guilabel>Installed Forge Runtimes</guilabel> list select the runtime and click <guibutton>Remove</guibutton>.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>To set a runtime server as the default, select the check box corresponding to the Forge runtime server. This runtime server will be used when Forge starts.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <application>Preferences</application> window.</para>
		
		<important><para>It is not possible to edit or delete the Forge runtime server that is distributed with Forge Tools. Additionally, it is not possible to delete a Forge runtime server that is selected as the default. You must first select a different runtime server as the default.</para></important>

	</section>

</section>

