<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Red_Hat_JBoss_Developer_Studio_Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Determine_current_Java_developer_kit_in_use" remap="TID_13336">
	<sectioninfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>
				JBDS 7.0.0
			</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</sectioninfo>
	<title>Determine Default Java Developer Kit of the System</title>
	<para>
		To determine if your system has a Java developer kit set up for use and the version, follow the procedure below which is suitable for all operating systems.
	</para>
	<!-- Info from http://introcs.cs.princeton.edu/java/15inout/windows-cmd.html -->
	<procedure>
		<title>Determine Default Java Developer Kit of the System</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				On the command line, enter <command>javac -version</command>. The output shows the version of the Java compiler being used as the default of the system and indicates that the system has a Java developer kit set up for use.
			</para>
			<important>
				<para>
					If a message to the effect of <command>javac not found</command> is returned, the system does not have a Java compiler set up for use. This indicates that either the system does not have a Java developer kit installed or that the installed Java developer kit is not set up for use.
				</para>
			</important>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				On the command line, enter <command>java -version</command>. The output preceding <command>Runtime Environment</command> identifies which Java distribution is being used as the default Java runtime environment (JRE) and the output after <command>java version</command> identifies the version number of the JRE.
			</para>
			<important>
				<para>
					If the version numbers of the Java compiler and JRE are different, the system is using a Java compiler and JRE from different Java distributions as the default. This should be rectified so that the Java compiler and JRE are from the same Java developer kit.
				</para>
			</important>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		Sample output for various Java developer kits is displayed below.
	</para>
	<example>
		<title>Sample Output from Identifying the Default Java Developer Kit of the System</title>
		<para>
			Output for OpenJDK Java developer kit 1.7.0: 
			<screen>
$ javac  -version
javac 1.7.0_09
$ java -version
java version "1.7.0_09-icedtea"
OpenJDK Runtime Environment (fedora-2.3.5.fc17-x86_64)
OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (build 23.2-b09, mixed mode)
			</screen> Output for Oracle JDK 1.6.0: 
			<screen>			
$ javac -version
javac 1.6.0_38
$ java -version
java version "1.6.0_38"
Java(TM) SE Runtime Environment (build 1.6.0_38-b05)
Java HotSpot(TM) 64-Bit Server VM (build 20.13-b02, mixed mode)
			</screen> Output for OpenJDK JRE 1.7.0 (no Java compiler): 
			<screen>
$ javac -version
bash: /usr/bin/javac: No such file or directory
$ java -version
java version "1.7.0_09-icedtea"
OpenJDK Runtime Environment (fedora-2.3.5.fc17-x86_64)
OpenJDK Server VM (build 23.2-b09, mixed mode)
			</screen>
		</para>
	</example>
</section>