<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Getting_Started_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Getting_Started_with_JBoss_Developer_Studio">
	<title>Getting Started with JBoss Developer Studio</title>
	<section id="About_Getting_Started" remap="TID_13787">
		<title>About Getting Started</title>
		<para>
			Getting Started is a step-by-step guide that introduces JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio to new users. It aims to give you a taste of developing applications with JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio.
		</para>
		<para>
			The guide covers three topics: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						how to install and set up JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						how to create a web application, TicketMonster, with JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						how to uninstall JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist> In guiding you through these topics, a number of assumptions are made about your system. The assumptions are associated with installing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio and working through the TicketMonster tutorial and they are detailed in the appropriate sections of the guide.
		</para>
		<para>
			Additionally, the information in the guide is minimal. It describes one method of installing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio and one way of completing each step in the TicketMonster tutorial. In fact, there is more than one method to install JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio and there may be several alternatives for each step in the TicketMonster tutorial. For more information about the alternative installation methods and alternative ways to complete tasks, see Red&nbsp;Hat JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 Installation Guide and User Guide.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>