<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Red_Hat_JBoss_Developer_Studio_Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="chap-Set_Preferences_on_First_Launch_after_Installing">
	<title>Set Preferences on First Launch after Installing</title>
	<section id="Preferences_Options" remap="TID_15790">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Preferences Options</title>
		<para>
			The aim of this section is to guide you in setting preferences for the JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio features encountered on the first IDE start after installing: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Set up a workspace that will contain your projects
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Choose whether to enable JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio to collect usage information for compiling product-wide statistics
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Activate the JBoss perspective to provide easy access to common tabs, menus and toolbars for working with JBoss technologies
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Specify the locations where JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio should automatically search for new runtime servers and so save you from setting up each one individually
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Select_a_Workspace_Location" remap="TID_13347">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Select a Workspace Location</title>
		<para>
			When the IDE starts, you are asked to choose the workspace folder for the session. The workspace is where your projects are stored.
		</para>
		<para>
			To set the workspace location, follow these steps: 
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						In the <guilabel>Workspace</guilabel> field type the full path of the desired location or use <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to navigate to the desired location.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you do not want to be asked to choose a workspace folder each time the development environment starts, select the <guilabel>Use this as the default and do not ask again</guilabel> check box.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		<para>
			The workspace location prompting behavior can be altered at any time by clicking <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. Expand <guilabel>General</guilabel>&rarr;<guilabel>Startup and Shutdown</guilabel> and select <guilabel>Workspaces</guilabel>. Select or clear the <guilabel>Prompt for workspace on startup</guilabel> check box to alter the behavior as appropriate.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Set_Usage_Reporting" remap="TID_13335">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Set Usage Reporting</title>
		<para>
			JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio has usage reporting. At the first start of the development environment after installing, you are asked if you allow the collection of anonymous usage statistics by JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio. The information collected enables Red Hat to understand how and where JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio is being used. Specifically, information about operating systems and displays assists to continually improve JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio.
		</para>
		<para>
			The following information is collected: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Installed components of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						JBoss Central enabled
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Origin of Eclipse product
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Version of Eclipse
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Operating system
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Operating system version
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Linux distribution and version, if appropriate
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Screen colors
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Screen resolution
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Version of Java
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Internet connection type
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Location (continent, country, city) and language
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						User type (new or returning)
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Number of times JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio has been started
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Date of first usage reported
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Date of last usage reported
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Date of current usage reported
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		<para>
			If enabled, the usage reporting plug-in uses Google Analytics to track data as though you visited a page under <ulink url="https://devstudio.jboss.com/usage"/>.
		</para>
		<para>
			To agree to this anonymous information being collected, click <guibutton>Yes</guibutton> when prompted.
		</para>
		<para>
			The usage reporting behavior can be changed at any time by clicking <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. Expand <guilabel>JBoss Tools</guilabel> and select <guilabel>Usage Reporting</guilabel>. Select or clear the <guilabel>Please allow Red Hat Inc. to receive anonymous usage statistics for this JBoss Developer Studio installation</guilabel> check box to alter the behavior as appropriate.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Set_the_Perspective_to_JBoss" remap="TID_13346">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Set the Perspective to JBoss</title>
		<para>
			JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio has JBoss perspective. This displays tabs, toolbars and menu items most often used by developers using JBoss. These include Project Explorer, Palette, Servers and OpenShift Explorer.
		</para>
		<para>
			If you start JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio, this perspective is set as the default and it is automatically displayed.
		</para>
		<para>
			If you start Eclipse, this perspective is not automatically displayed. To show the JBoss perspective, click the <guibutton>JBoss</guibutton> icon. Alternatively, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Open Perspective</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Other</guimenu> and select <application>JBoss</application>.
		</para>
		<para>
			To set JBoss perspective as the default perspective, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. Expand <guilabel>General</guilabel> and select <guilabel>Perspectives</guilabel>. Select <application>JBoss</application> from the list of available perspectives and click <guibutton>Make Default</guibutton>. Click <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Preferences</guilabel> window.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Set_up_Automatic_Runtime_Detection" remap="TID_13345">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Set up Automatic Runtime Detection</title>
		<para>
			JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio has automatic runtime detection for finding runtime servers. This can be set up to scan locations for runtime servers when a new workspace is created or the IDE starts.
		</para>
		<para>
			You may have already set this up during the installation process with the JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio installer. If you have not set this up or you installed JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio though Eclipse Marketplace, follow the procedure below to set up automatic runtime detection.
		</para>
		<procedure>
			<title>Set up Automatic Runtime Detection</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>, expand <guilabel>JBoss Tools</guilabel> and select <guilabel>JBoss Tools Runtime Detection</guilabel>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					To add a path for scanning, click <guibutton>Add</guibutton> and select a folder from which recursive scanning should commence. JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio scans this folder and any subfolders to check for new runtime servers.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					If new runtime servers are found, you can create instances of them. Select the check boxes of the runtime servers you want to create and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>. If no runtime servers were found or you do not wish to create any instances click <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton>. In all cases, the path is added to the list of paths for scanning.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					If you want this path to be scanned for runtime servers each time the IDE starts, select the <guilabel>Every start</guilabel> check box for the new path.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Click <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> to save any new paths and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Preferences</guilabel> window.
				</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
	</section>
</chapter>