<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Red_Hat_JBoss_Developer_Studio_Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="chap-Install_JBoss_Developer_Studio">
	<title>Install JBoss Developer Studio</title>
	<section id="Install_Options" remap="TID_13339">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Install Options</title>
		<para>
			JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio can be installed in a number of different ways.
		</para>
		<para>
			You can install JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio, packaged with Eclipse and dependent third party plug-ins, with a universal installer for all operating systems.
		</para>
		<para>
			Alternatively, if you already have Eclipse on your system you may prefer to install JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE. This option installs JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio onto Eclipse.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Install_with_the_JAR_Installer" remap="TID_13342">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Install JBoss Developer Studio</title>
		<para>
			<remark>
				[QE]A universal installer <filename>.jar</filename> file is provided for installing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio and it is available from the Customer Service Portal. 
			</remark>
		</para>
		<para>
			<remark>
				[QE]Alternatively, the source code is also available as a <filename>.zip</filename> file at the same location. You can use this source code to build the universal installer yourself and then use that to install JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio. Maven must be installed to build the universal installer from the source code.
			</remark>
		</para>
		<para>
			<remark>
				[QE]Both options are detailed in the procedure below.
			</remark>
		</para>
		<procedure>
			<title>Install with the Universal Installer</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					Log in to the Customer Service Portal at <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com">https://access.redhat.com</ulink>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					From the menu bar click <guimenu>Downloads</guimenu> then, under <guimenu>JBOSS ENTERPRISE MIDDLEWARE</guimenu>, click <guimenu>Downloads</guimenu>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					From the <guilabel>Product</guilabel> list, select <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio</guilabel>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					<remark>
						[QE, whole new step]
					</remark> Complete the appropriate step for your chosen install option:
				</para>
				<stepalternatives>
					<step>
						<para>
							For installing from the provided universal installer, from the <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio 7</guilabel> table click <guibutton>Download</guibutton> for the <filename>JBoss Developer Studio 7.0.0 Stand Alone Universal Binary</filename> download file.
						</para>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>
							For installing from a source-built universal installer, follow these steps:
						</para>
						<substeps>
							<step>
								<para>
									From the <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio 7</guilabel> table, click <guibutton>Download</guibutton> for the <filename>JBoss Developer Studio 7.0.0 Source Code</filename> download file.
								</para>
							</step>
							<step>
								<para>
									On the command line, navigate to the location of the <filename>.zip</filename> file and enter 
									<screen>unzip jbdevstudio-product-sources-7.0.0.<replaceable>build_version</replaceable>.zip</screen> where <replaceable>build_version</replaceable> is substituted to match the name of the downloaded file.
								</para>
							</step>
							<step>
								<para>
									To build the universal installer, on the command line navigate to <filename>devstudio/product</filename> and enter 
									<screen>mvn clean install</screen> Building takes some time to complete, after which the universal installer <filename>.jar</filename> file is located in <filename>installer/target/</filename>.
								</para>
							</step>
						</substeps>
					</step>
				</stepalternatives>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					On the command line, navigate to the location of the universal installer <filename>.jar</filename> file and enter 
					<screen>java -jar jbdevstudio-product_universal-7.0.0.<replaceable>build_version</replaceable>.jar</screen> where <replaceable>build_version</replaceable> is substituted to match the name of the <filename>.jar</filename> file. 
					<note>
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									To start the installer, you may be able to double-click the <filename>.jar</filename> file.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									To force a 32-bit or 64-bit installation of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio, append <command>-d32</command> or <command>-d64</command> to the <command>java</command> command, respectively. For example, 
									<screen>java -jar -d32 jbdevstudio-product_universal-7.0.0.<replaceable>build_version</replaceable>.jar</screen>
								</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
					</note>
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					When the <guilabel>Installer</guilabel> window opens, click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					After reading and agreeing to the terms of the End User License Agreement, click <guilabel>I accept the terms of this license agreement</guilabel> and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					In the <guilabel>Select the installation path</guilabel> field, type the location where you want JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio to be installed or click <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to navigate to the desired location. When the <guilabel>Select the installation path</guilabel> field shows the correct location, click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>. When you are prompted about the selected location being created or overwritten, check the message and, if satisfied, click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					<guilabel>Default Java VM</guilabel> is automatically selected. Check that the disabled text field contains the path of the JRE in the Java developer kit you want to use. If it does not, click <guilabel>Specific Java JVM</guilabel> and type the path of the JRE in the text field or use the <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> button to select the correct JRE. When the text field shows the correct JRE path, click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					To make use of automatic runtime detection for finding runtime servers, click <guibutton>Add</guibutton> and type the path of a runtime server in the <guilabel>Location</guilabel> field or click <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to navigate to the runtime server location. If you want this path to be scanned for new runtime servers each time JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio starts, select the <guilabel>Scan every start</guilabel> check box. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Add Location</guilabel> window and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Check the details in the <application>Summary Information</application> window and, if they are correct, click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Installation commences. When the <guilabel>Pack installation progress</guilabel> bar shows <guilabel>Finished</guilabel>, click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					If you want shortcuts to be created for starting JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio, select the <guilabel>Create shortcuts in the Start-Menu</guilabel> and <guilabel>Create additional shortcut on the desktop</guilabel> check boxes and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					The installation process is now complete. If you want JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio to automatically start when the <guilabel>Installer</guilabel> window closes, select the <guilabel>Run JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio after installation</guilabel> check box. Click <guibutton>Done</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Installer</guilabel> window.
				</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
		<important>
			<para>
				Linux distributions have a maximum number of files that a process may have open at one time. If this maximum number of files is set too low, JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio will not start. You must open the <filename>/etc/security/limits.conf</filename> file and check that the <command>soft nofile</command> and <command>hard nofile</command> variables have values of <command>9216</command> at a minimum. If the variables have smaller values, the values must be increased to <command>9216</command>. If the variables are not specified, the following lines must be added to the file: 
				<screen>* soft nofile 9216
* hard nofile 9216</screen>
			</para>
		</important>
	</section>
	<section id="Install_from_Eclipse_Marketplace" remap="TID_13343">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Install JBoss Developer Studio BYOE</title>
		<para>
			<remark>
				[QE]You can obtain JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE from Eclipse Marketplace or use the universal installer <filename>.jar</filename> file available from the Customer Service Portal.
			</remark>
		</para>
		<para>
			<remark>
				[QE]You can also use the source code <filename>.zip</filename> file available from the Customer Service Portal to build the universal installer yourself and then proceed with installing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE. Maven must be installed to build the universal installer from the source code.
			</remark>
		</para>
		<para>
			<remark>
				[QE] The procedures below guide you through all of these methods.
			</remark>
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				<remark>
					[QE]When using the universal installer, you can conduct the installation process offline once the installer or source code has been downloaded. But, when installing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE from Eclipse Marketplace you must remain connected to the internet for the duration of the installation process.
				</remark>
			</para>
		</note>
		<procedure>
			<title>Install from Eclipse Marketplace</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					Start Eclipse Kepler.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Click <guimenu>Help</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Eclipse Marketplace</guimenu>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					In the <guilabel>Find</guilabel> field of the <guilabel>Search</guilabel> tab, type <command>JBoss Developer Studio</command> and press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Locate <application>JBoss Developer Studio (Kepler)</application> and click <guibutton>Install</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Ensure the <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio (Kepler)</guilabel> check box is selected and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					After reading and agreeing to the licenses, click <guilabel>I accept the terms of the license agreements</guilabel> and click <guibutton>Finish</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					During the installation process you may receive warnings about installing unsigned content. If this is the case, check the details of the content and if satisfied click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to continue with the installation.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Once installing is complete, you are prompted to restart Eclipse. Click <guibutton>Yes</guibutton> to restart now and <guibutton>No</guibutton> if you need to save any unsaved changes to open projects. Note that changes do not take effect until Eclipse is restarted.
				</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
		<procedure>
			<title><remark>[QE], whole procedure</remark>Install with the Universal Installer</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					Log in to the Customer Service Portal at <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com">https://access.redhat.com</ulink>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					From the menu bar click <guimenu>Downloads</guimenu> then, under <guimenu>JBOSS ENTERPRISE MIDDLEWARE</guimenu>, click <guimenu>Downloads</guimenu>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					From the <guilabel>Product</guilabel> list, select <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio</guilabel>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Complete the appropriate step for your chosen install option:
				</para>
				<stepalternatives>
					<step>
						<para>
							For installing from the provided universal installer, from the <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio 7</guilabel> table click <guibutton>Download</guibutton> for the <filename>JBoss Developer Studio 7.0.0 Stand Alone Universal Binary</filename> download file.
						</para>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>
							For installing from a source-built universal installer, follow these steps:
						</para>
						<substeps>
							<step>
								<para>
									From the <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio 7</guilabel> table, click <guibutton>Download</guibutton> for the <filename>JBoss Developer Studio 7.0.0 Source Code</filename> download file.
								</para>
							</step>
							<step>
								<para>
									On the command line, navigate to the location of the <filename>.zip</filename> file and enter 
									<screen>unzip jbdevstudio-product-sources-7.0.0.<replaceable>build_version</replaceable>.zip</screen> where <replaceable>build_version</replaceable> is substituted to match the name of the downloaded file.
								</para>
							</step>
							<step>
								<para>
									To build the universal installer, on the command line navigate to <filename>devstudio/product</filename> and enter 
									<screen>mvn clean install</screen> Building takes some time to complete, after which the universal installer <filename>.jar</filename> file is located in <filename>installer/target/</filename>.
								</para>
							</step>
						</substeps>
					</step>
				</stepalternatives>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Start Eclipse Kepler.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Click <guimenu>Help</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Install New Software</guimenu>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					In the <guilabel>Work with</guilabel> field, enter the absolute file path of the universal installer <filename>.jar</filename> file. Alternatively, click <guibutton>Add</guibutton> and click <guibutton>Archive</guibutton> to locate the file.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					From the table of components comprising the universal installer, select the <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio 7.0 - Bring Your Own Eclipse</guilabel> and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Verify the details of the component to be installed and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					After reading and agreeing to the licenses, click <guilabel>I accept the terms of the license agreements</guilabel> and click <guibutton>Finish</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					During the installation process you may receive warnings about installing unsigned content. If this is the case, check the details of the content and if satisfied click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to continue with the installation.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Once installing is complete, you are prompted to restart Eclipse. Click <guibutton>Yes</guibutton> to restart now and <guibutton>No</guibutton> if you need to save any unsaved changes to open projects. Note that changes do not take effect until Eclipse is restarted.
				</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
	</section>
</chapter>