<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Issues-fixed-in-this-release">
    <title>
        Enhancements and fixed issues in version 6.0.0
    </title>
	<variablelist>
		<!-- JBIDE-12934 -->
		<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12934">JBIDE-12934</ulink>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				A bug existed that would cause an error state to still display at the endpoint node of a JAX-RS Resource Method. This was viewable in the project explorer view. Correct behaviour has been implemented for this release, displaying warning and error markers at the endpoint and JAX-RS REST Web Services node levels.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	
	<!-- JBIDE-12842 -->
	<varlistentry>
	<term>
		<ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12842">JBIDE-12842</ulink>
	</term>
	<listitem>
		<para>
			Fuse previously included Hibernate Tools runtime JAR files that were created based on a snapshot rather than an official build. These files have now been replaced with official builds. Users should not notice any functionality changes based on this.
		</para>
	</listitem>
</varlistentry>


   <!-- JBIDE-12793 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12793">JBIDE-12793</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   A new wizard has been created that allows for the registering of Service implementations. The wizard adds an existing class that implements an interface, to an appropriate META-INF/services file, or creates the Service file if it does not exist. A user can access this wizard either through the wizard selection screen or by using the keyboard shortcut Ctrl+Shift+F10.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12781 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12781">JBIDE-12781</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   The JSF project wizard now allows for the creation of a JSF 2.1 project.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12709 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12709">JBIDE-12709</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   The JBoss server editor would insist a user provide their password just to access the editor. This issue has been resolved by modifying the ServerPasswordSection.java file so a password is only required when appropriate options are changed within the server editor.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12655 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12655">JBIDE-12655</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   Prior versions of OpenShift tooling created and uploaded public SSH keys to the OpenShift server when the user was creating the domain. This caused troubles when the user created the domain outside Eclipse (web console or command line) since the tooling was not prompting the user to upload keys to OpenShift. This has been corrected by now allowing SSH keys to be created and uploaded through a specific wizard. Furthermore the application wizard now errors if no keys are on the OpenShift server.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12633 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12633">JBIDE-12633</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   Support has been added for JAX-RS Application subclassing by allowing a user to place a corresponding configuration in the web.xml file of the application.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12551 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12551">JBIDE-12551</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   When pressing the Reset button within the Convert to maven dependencies wizard, the dependencies lookup was still not reset. The issue has been correct by replacing the Reset button with a Identify Dependencies button. Through this new button a user can relaunch dependency identification after updating the Maven repositories list within settings.xml, or enabling new remote nexus repositories.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12390 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12390">JBIDE-12390</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   A new quick fix has been implemented for the WTP issue marker: Missing required attribute. The new quick fix allows for the missing attributes to be automatically added into the code being written.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12166 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12166">JBIDE-12166</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   The ability to generate blank archetypes for Java EE 6 (WAR and EAR), HTML5, RichFaces, Spring and GWT has been added to each relevant wizard. This assist users in creating a new archetype that is not based on provided demo code.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-11912 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-11912">JBIDE-11912</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   A user can now manage their SSH public keys that are on the OpenShift server. You are now able to create and upload new keys, and remove existing keys. The SSH keys wizard is available through the context menu of OpenShift Explorer and when he's creating or importing an OpenShift application. The page dedicated to the git clone settings holds a link to the SSH preferences and the SSH keys wizard.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-10287 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-10287">JBIDE-10287</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   Support for JAX-RS applications has been added. An applications path can be configured by using the @ApplicationPath annotation on a Java type, or by configuring the javax.ws.rs.core.Application class in the web.xml servlet-mappings.
	   </para>
	   <para>
		   If a user implements both approaches, the web.xml configuration will override the annotation.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-9443 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-9443">JBIDE-9443</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         A new wizard called New Service Provider Class has been added for the creation of service implementations. Through the wizard a user can create a Service Provider Java class for a selected Service Type.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>




   <!-- JBIDE-7996 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-7996">JBIDE-7996</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         A new feature has been added allowing for a user to import existing DTP connection settings when using the Hibernate Configuration File wizard. For a user this means an existing DTP connection can be selected and the settings imported for use in the configuration file being created.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

</variablelist>


</section>
