<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Issues-fixed-in-this-release">
     <title>
        Resolved Issues
    </title>
<variablelist>
   <!-- JBDS-2284 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBDS-2284">JBDS-2284</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         A limited number of third party extensions and tools could be installed from the JBoss Developer Studio Extras site. Incompatibility between some of the third party products and Tycho, a set of plug-ins for Eclipse used to build update sites, made maintaining their provision difficult. To resolve this issue, FindBugs, PMD and Android Tooling are now only available through JBoss Central.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBDS-2365 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBDS-2365">JBDS-2365</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         JBoss Enterprise Service Bus (ESB) 4.11 and 4.12 projects were not recognized as compatible for deploying on runtime server instances of JBoss Enterprise Application Platform and JBoss Application Server and, as a result, the associated applications could not be deployed to these servers. The list of compatible facets held by Server Tools has been extended to include JBoss ESB 4.11 and 4.12. Consequently, the applications of JBoss ESB 4.11 and 4.12 projects can now be deployed on runtime server instances of JBoss Enterprise Application Platform and JBoss Application Server without errors or warnings.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- Documented in section: Component Versions -->
   <!-- JBDS-2438 -->
   <!--<varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBDS-2438">JBDS-2438</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         A universal installer that includes JBoss Enterprise Application Platform is available for each release of JBoss Developer Studio. Previously, JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 6.0.0 was included. JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 6.0.1 has now been released, which fixes issues in JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 6.0.0. Consequently, JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 6.0.1 is now included in the combined universal installer.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry> -->

   <!-- JBIDE-10398 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-10398">JBIDE-10398</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         EGit provides tooling for Git in Eclipse and it is used by applications deployed to OpenShift. Previously the EGit cache held references to the files in a project and these references prevented workspace projects from being deleted on Microsoft Windows operating systems. Consequently, the projects of OpenShift applications that were imported into the workspace could not be deleted. A patch was submitted to EGit and it was accepted and applied to EGit 2.3.1 (Eclipse Juno SR2). The Git cache now releases references to missing files so projects of OpenShift applications can be deleted from the workspace on Microsoft Windows operating systems.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBIDE-12901 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12901">JBIDE-12901</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         Through the Remote Server Explorer (RSE), file systems on remote servers can be viewed and managed.  Previously, when an archived file was expanded in RSE it caused an exception to occur. A patch was submitted to RSE and it was accepted and applied to RSE 3.4.2 (Eclipse Juno SR2). The RSE now checks that the element to be expanded is a directory before performing the expansion and, consequently, exceptions relating to expanding archived files no longer occur.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBIDE-13213 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13213">JBIDE-13213</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         Project Archives capabilities for a project could previously only be set through the Project Archives view. To make it easier to find and more intuitive to use, this functionality has also been added to the context menu for a project. Now Project Archives capabilities can be added and removed from a project by right-clicking on a project and selecting Configure-&gt;Add Project Archives Support or Configure-&gt;Remove Project Archives Support, respectively. This can be accessed in Navigator, Project Explorer and Java Package Explorer views.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBIDE-13263 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13263">JBIDE-13263</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         By default, JBoss Application Server deployment scanners monitor the workspace metadata for applications to deploy. API changes caused duplicate deployment scanners to be created for JBoss Application Server 7. In rectifying this issue, tooling modifications inadvertently caused no deployment scanners to be created for JBoss Application Server 6. As a result, applications selected for deployment on JBoss Application Server 6 failed to deploy. Modifications have been reworked to ensure a deployment scanner is created for JBoss Application Server 6 and, consequently, applications will deploy to JBoss Application Server 6.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- Withdrawn -->
   <!-- JBIDE-13335 -->
   <!--<varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13335">JBIDE-13335</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         Following the release of JBoss Developer Studio 6.0.0, Eclipse released an optimization patch for Eclipse Juno SR1 to resolve some of its known issues. To ensure users of JBoss Developer Studio could benefit from this patch, a connector was included in JBoss Central to apply the patch. The issues resolved by the optimization patch are now incorporated in Eclipse Juno SR2 and, accordingly, JBoss Developer Studio 6.0.1 provided by the universal installer. Consequently, the connector is no longer needed and it has been removed from JBoss Central in JBoss Developer Studio 6.0.1.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry> -->

   <!-- JBIDE-13346 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13346">JBIDE-13346</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         Deployment Assembly is used to control which files should be deployed with an application to the runtime server and it can be accessed via the Properties of a project. Previously, if Deployment Assembly contained information about nonexistent directories, error messages were generated when the project was built. These error messages were noncritical and did not have an impact on the project's build success. Server Tools has been amended so that it no longer logs the noncritical error messages for nonexistent directories and, consequently, these error messages do not appear in error logs of project builds.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBIDE-13537 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13537">JBIDE-13537</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 6.1 has a different module directory structure to previous releases of JBoss Enterprise Application Platform. Consequently, JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 6.1 was not recognized with either the new server wizard, runtime detection or Server-&gt;Runtime Environments in Preferences and servers could not be created. A new JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 6.1 (Tech Preview) server adapter has been created and integrated into the existing tooling. This recognizes JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 6.1 and allows associated server instances to be created.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBIDE-13601 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13601">JBIDE-13601</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         GWT web projects must be compiled using GWT Compile before being deployed on the server. However, GWT Compile did not create the required Errai classes when compiling GWT web projects and, as a result, errors occurred during application deployment. To solve this issue, the Maven Configurator Plug-in for GWT was modified. Now GWT Compile creates the required Errai classes and applications deploy without errors.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBIDE-13602 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13602">JBIDE-13602</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         The project wizards in JBoss central are based on Maven archetypes and stacks.yml holds information defining the archetype for each project. Occasionally, stacks.yml would not load correctly and archetype information necessary for building the project would not be available. As a result, the wizard description would show "Project based on the null:null:null Maven archetype" and the project would fail to be created, with the error "Root cause: For artifact null:null:null:pom". The tooling has been modified to ensure stack.yml is always correctly loaded. Consequently, the wizard does not show null in the Maven archetype information and the project is successfully created.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>


   <!-- JBIDE-13683 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13683">JBIDE-13683</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         Runtime detection is used to recognize and create instances of runtime servers. Although runtime detection recognized JBoss Portal Platform installations as runtime servers, it failed to create associated server instances. This issue has been resolved by updating the server bean loaders to identify JBoss Portal Platform runtime servers more specifically and by updating the runtime detection to ensure no likely server types are ignored in the future. As a result, JBoss Portal Platform runtime servers are now recognized and instantiated by runtime detection.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBIDE-13690 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13690">JBIDE-13690</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         Application server directory trees were expected to have a certain structure, which was relied upon for the tooling to recognize and create new application servers. As highlighted by <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-13537">JBIDE-13537</ulink>, new releases of application servers do not necessarily conform to the expected directory structure. Consequently, these application servers would not be recognized by the tooling and would require patches to rectify the issues. To make recognition more reliable for future releases of application severs, the recognition methods have been modified to recognize a wider range of possible directory structures, under the provision that the directory structure does not deviate too far from the currently known structures.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

</variablelist>





</section>
