<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Known_Issues_with_this_release">
	<title>
			Known Issues in version 5.0.2
	</title>

<variablelist>

   <!-- JBDS-2364 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBDS-2364">JBDS-2364</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         An issue arises when importing existing Maven projects. The m2e connector for build-helper-maven-plugin is required but installation fails due to an unsatisfied dependency for org.eclipse.m2e.jdt, which requires versions higher than 1.1.0 (and lower than 2.0.0) when only 1.0.x is available. This issue remains unresolved but users can work around it by using JBoss Developer Studio 6.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

   <!-- JBDS-1786 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBDS-1786">JBDS-1786</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         Downloading m2e from the Eclipse Marketplace or other sites and installing in JBoss Developer Studio can fail due to incompatibility and missing requirements. m2e certified for use with JBoss Developer Studio 5 must be obtained from the JBoss Developer Studio Extras website.
         </para>
         <para>
         Install the certified m2e plug-in from within JBoss Developer Studio by clicking <application>Help > Install New Software</application> to open the <application>Available Software</application> window. In the <application>Work with</application> combination box select <application>JBoss Developer Studio 5.0 Extras</application> or type the location of the Extras site <ulink url="https://devstudio.jboss.com/updates/5.0/extras/">https://devstudio.jboss.com/updates/5.0/extras/</ulink> to view packages for installation. Selecting the <application>Maven Integration - Extras</application> check box under <application>JBoss Selected Features</application> and completing the installation wizard will make m2e functionality available in JBoss Developer Studio 5.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

</variablelist>

</section>
