<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Migration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Upgrade_from_Previous_Versions_of_JBoss_Developer_Studio">
	<title>Upgrade from Previous Versions of JBoss Developer Studio</title>
	<section id="Upgrade_Methods" remap="TID_13419">
		<title>Upgrade Methods</title>
		<para>
			The method for upgrading JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio depends on the version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio from which you are upgrading.
		</para>
		<warning>
			<para>
				Before upgrading, you are advised to back up your workspace. In addition to your project files, your workspace contains meta-data about customized setting and preferences for the IDE. To back up your workspace, either copy the workspace directory to a backup location or save it as a compressed file.
			</para>
		</warning>
	</section>
	<section id="Upgrade_from_JBoss_Developer_Studio_6.x_and_Earlier" remap="TID_22604">
		<title>Upgrade from JBoss Developer Studio 6.x and Earlier</title>
		<para>
			It is not possible to upgrade an existing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 6.x or earlier installation to JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 because they are based on different versions of Eclipse. For example, JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 6.0 is based on Eclipse Juno (4.2) but JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 is based on Eclipse Kepler (4.3).
		</para>
		<para>
			To use JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1, you must do one of the following: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						For JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio, download and run the JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 universal installer available from <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com"/> on the Red&nbsp;Hat Customer Portal.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						For JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE, upgrade to Eclipse Kepler (4.3) and install JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 BYOE from one of the following options: Eclipse Marketplace, the update <filename>.zip</filename> file available from the Red&nbsp;Hat Customer Portal or from <ulink url="https://devstudio.jboss.com/updates/7.0/"/> on the Red Hat JBoss Developer Studio Update website.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				You can use different versions of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio or JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE alongside each other by installing them in different directories or installing them onto different Eclipse installations, respectively.
			</para>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section id="Upgrade_from_JBoss_Developer_Studio_7.0" remap="TID_22704">
		<title>Upgrade from JBoss Developer Studio 7.0</title>
		<para>
			It is possible to upgrade an existing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.0 installation to JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 because they are based on the same version of Eclipse, namely Kepler (4.3).
		</para>
		<para>
			You may be automatically notified by the IDE when the JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 upgrade is available, depending on your IDE settings for automatic updates. Alternatively, the upgrade method stated here is applicable to JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio and JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE.
		</para>
		<para>
			To manually initiate the upgrade to JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1, in the IDE click <guimenu>Help</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Check for Updates</guimenu>. The <guilabel>Contacting Software Sites</guilabel> window opens and searches for updates to apply. If any updates are found they are listed in the <guilabel>Available Updates</guilabel> window. Ensure the check box for JBoss Developer Studio 7.1.0 is selected and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>. After reading and agreeing to the licenses, click <guilabel>I accept the terms of the license agreements</guilabel> and click <guibutton>Finish</guibutton>.
		</para>
		<para>
			During the installation process you may receive warnings about installing unsigned content. If this is the case, review the details of the content and if satisfied click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to continue with the installation. Once installing is complete, you are prompted to restart the IDE. Click <guibutton>Yes</guibutton> to restart now and <guibutton>No</guibutton> if you need to save any unsaved changes to open projects. Note that IDE changes do not take effect until the IDE is restarted.
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				If you are expecting updates but none are found, check that the IDE is aware of the URL where JBoss Developer Studio updates are located. Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>, expand <guilabel>Install/Update</guilabel> and click <guilabel>Available Software Sites</guilabel>. In the table of <guilabel>Available Software Sites</guilabel> the URL <ulink url="https://devstudio.jboss.com/updates/7.0/"/> must be listed. If it is not listed, click <guibutton>Add</guibutton> and in the <guilabel>Location</guilabel> field type the URL. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Add Site</guilabel> window and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Preferences</guilabel> window.
			</para>
		</note>
		<important>
			<para>
				If you have installed additional plug-ins from JBoss Central and updated versions of these plug-ins are available with this release of JBoss Developer Studio, you must upgrade the plug-ins independently after first upgrading JBoss Developer Studio. To install the updated version of an already installed plug-in, from the JBoss Central <guilabel>Software/Update</guilabel> tab select to install the plug-in as if it is new and follow the installation wizard instructions.
			</para>
		</important>
	</section>
</chapter>