<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Migration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Getting_Help_and_Giving_Feedback2" remap="TID_23618">
	<title>Getting Help and Giving Feedback</title>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Do You Need Help?</title>
		<para>
			If you experience difficulty with a procedure described in this documentation, visit the <phrase>Red Hat Customer Portal at <ulink url="http://access.redhat.com"/></phrase>. Through the <phrase>customer portal</phrase>, you can:
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				search or browse through a knowledgebase of technical support articles about Red Hat products.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				submit a support case to Red Hat Global Support Services (GSS).
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				access other product documentation.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		Red Hat also hosts a large number of electronic mailing lists for discussion of Red Hat software and technology. You can find a list of publicly available mailing lists at <ulink url="https://www.redhat.com/mailman/listinfo"/>. Click on the name of any mailing list to subscribe to that list or to access the list archives.
	</para>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Give us Feedback</title>
		<para>
			If you find a typographical error or have a suggestion for improving this documentation, we would love to hear from you. Submit a report in JIRA against the project <application>Documentation for JBoss Tools and Developer Studio (TOOLSDOC)</application>. The following link will take you to a pre-filled bug report for this product: <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/secure/CreateIssueDetails!init.jspa?issuetype=1&amp;pid=12310980">https://issues.jboss.org</ulink>.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<para>
		Fill out the following template in JIRA's <guilabel>Description</guilabel> field. Be as specific as possible when describing the issue; this will help ensure that we can fix it quickly.
	</para>
	<screen>Document URL:

Section Number and Name:

Describe the issue:

Suggestions for improvement:

Additional information:

</screen>
	<para>
		Be sure to give us your name so that you can receive full credit for reporting the issue.
	</para>
</section>