<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE appendix PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<appendix id="appe-Supplementary_Installation_Procedures">
	<title>Supplementary Installation Procedures</title>
	<section id="Build_the_Universal_Installer_from_Source" remap="TID_22678">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.1.z
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Build the Universal Installer from Source</title>
		<para/>
		<para>
			A source code <filename>.zip</filename> file is provided for building the JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio universal installer and it is available from the Customer Portal. The procedure below guides you though obtaining the source code and the build process.
		</para>
		<important>
			<para>
				Maven must be installed to build the universal installer from the source code. To obtain Maven see <ulink url="http://maven.apache.org/"/>.
			</para>
		</important>
		<procedure>
			<title>Build the Universal Installer from Source</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					Log into the Customer Portal at <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com">https://access.redhat.com</ulink>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					From the menu bar click <guimenu>Downloads</guimenu>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Under <guimenu>Red Hat JBoss Middleware</guimenu>, click <guimenu>Download Software</guimenu>.
				</para>
				<figure>
					<title>Download Red Hat JBoss Middleware Software on the Customer Portal</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/3846.png"/>
						</imageobject>
						<textobject>
							<phrase>Log in to the Customer Portal at <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com">https://access.redhat.com</ulink>. From the menu bar click <guimenu>Downloads</guimenu>. Under <guimenu>Red Hat JBoss Middleware</guimenu>, click <guimenu>Download Software</guimenu>.</phrase>
						</textobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Under <guilabel>Software Downloads</guilabel>, select the following options: 
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								From the <guilabel>Product</guilabel> list, select <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio</guilabel>.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								From the <guilabel>Version</guilabel> list, select <guilabel>7.1.x</guilabel>.
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				<!--<figure>
				<title>JBoss Developer Studio Downloads Listed on the Customer Portal</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/3358.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>Under <guilabel>Software Downloads</guilabel>, select the following options: From the <guilabel>Product</guilabel> list, select <guilabel>JBoss Developer Studio</guilabel>. From the <guilabel>Version</guilabel> list, select <guilabel>7.1.x</guilabel>.</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure> -->
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					From the table, click <guibutton>Download</guibutton> for the <filename>Red Hat JBoss Developer Studio 7.1.x Source Code</filename> download file. This downloads the sources <filename>.zip</filename> file.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					On the command line, navigate to <filename>path/to/.zip</filename> and enter 
					<screen>unzip jbdevstudio-product-sources-7.1.<replaceable>x.build_version</replaceable>.zip</screen> where <replaceable>x.build_version</replaceable> is substituted to match the name of the downloaded file. The archive is extracted to a <filename>devstudio</filename> directory.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					To build the universal installer, on the command line navigate to <filename>devstudio/product</filename> and enter 
					<screen>mvn clean install</screen> Building takes some time to complete, after which the universal installer <filename>.jar</filename> file is located in <filename>installer/target/</filename>.
				</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
	</section>
	<section id="Install_JBoss_Developer_Studio_via_Script" remap="TID_22679">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.1.z
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Install JBoss Developer Studio via Script</title>
		<para>
			Scripts are available for installing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio. These remove the need to step through the universal installer GUI, enabling simplified repeat installations or installations in bulk.
		</para>
		<para>
			There are two methods for completing scripted installations. The first method requires you to install JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio stepping through the universal installer GUI once and then use a generated script for subsequent installations. The second method requires you to download and run a script and then use a generated script for all installations. These different methods are detailed in the procedures below.
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				To install JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio using scripts, you must first download the universal installer <filename>.jar</filename> file. You can download the <filename>.jar</filename> file from <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com"/> on the Customer Portal website.
			</para>
		</note>
		<procedure>
			<title>Install Once and Use a Generated Script to Run Subsequent Installations</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					To run the universal installer GUI, on the command line enter 
					<screen>java -jar jbdevstudio-*.jar</screen>This generates a <filename>InstallConfigRecord.xml</filename> file in the directory where JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio is installed.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					To perform repeat installations without stepping through the universal installer GUI, on the command line enter 
					<screen>java -jar jbdevstudio-*.jar InstallConfigRecord.xml</screen>This creates an identically configured JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio installation.
				</para>
				<note>
					<para>
						The generated <filename>InstallConfigRecord.xml</filename> file is machine-specific, using the Java developer kit and installation paths of your system. To use the <filename>InstallConfigRecord.xml</filename> file for systems with different operating systems, Java developer kits or paths, you must manually modify the file.
					</para>
				</note>
			</step>
		</procedure>
		<procedure>
			<title>Run a Script and Use a Generated Script to Run All Installations</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					Download the shell script from the URL appropriate for your operating system:
				</para>
				<stepalternatives>
					<step>
						<para>
							For Microsoft Windows operating systems, <ulink url="https://devstudio.jboss.com/usage/scripted-install/jbds-install.cmd"/>
						</para>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>
							For OS X and Linux-based operating systems, <ulink url="https://devstudio.jboss.com/usage/scripted-install/jbds-install.sh"/>
						</para>
					</step>
				</stepalternatives>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					To run the shell script, follow instructions appropriate to your operating system:
				</para>
				<stepalternatives>
					<step>
						<para>
							For Microsoft Windows operating systems, on the command line enter 
							<screen>jbds-install.cmd</screen>
						</para>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>
							For OS X and Linux-based operating systems, on the command line enter 
							<screen>./jbds-install.sh</screen>
						</para>
					</step>
				</stepalternatives>
				<para>
					This generates a machine-specific <filename>jbdevstudio-*.install.xml</filename> file.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					To perform installations without stepping through the universal installer GUI, ensure the <filename>jbdevstudio-*.install.xml</filename> file is located in the same directory as the universal installer and on the command line enter 
					<screen>java -jar jbdevstudio-*.jar jbdevstudio-*.install.xml</screen>
				</para>
				<note>
					<para>
						The downloaded scripts specify a default Java developer kit to be used for installing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio: <filename>c:\progra~1\java\jre7\bin\java</filename> for Microsoft Windows operating systems and <filename>/usr/bin/java</filename> for OS X and Linux-based operating systems. To use a different Java developer kit, you must manually modify the downloaded script before running it to generate the <filename>jbdevstudio-*.install.xml</filename> file.
					</para>
				</note>
			</step>
		</procedure>
	</section>
</appendix>