<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-System_Requirements">
	<title>System Requirements</title>
	<section id="System_Requirements_Overview" remap="TID_15789">
		<title>System Requirements Overview</title>
		<para>
			The aim of this section is familiarize you with the system requirements necessary for JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio to function optimally: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A variety of operating system and architecture combinations are generally supported but some tools have additional requirements.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A minimum amount of RAM and hard disk space are required to install and run JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A variety of operating systems and Java developer kit combinations are supported.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Supported_Operating_Systems_and_Architectures" remap="TID_13331">
		<title>Supported Operating Systems and Architectures</title>
		<para>
			JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 is supported on the operating systems listed in the table below.
		</para>
		<table id="Supported_OS">
			<title>Supported Operating Systems</title>
			<tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colwidth="2*"/>
				<colspec colwidth="1*"/>
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Operating System
						</entry>
						<entry>
							Chip Architecture
						</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6
						</entry>
						<entry>
							x86, x86_64
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Microsoft Windows XP, Windows 7 and Windows 8
						</entry>
						<entry>
							x86, x86_64
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							OS X Lion (10.7) and OS X Mountain Lion (10.8)
						</entry>
						<entry>
							x86_64
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Fedora 18 and Fedora 19
						</entry>
						<entry>
							x86, x86_64
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Ubuntu 12.04.2 LTS and Ubuntu 13.04
						</entry>
						<entry>
							x86, x86_64
						</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
		<para>
			As JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 is based on Eclipse Kepler (4.3 SR1), the system requirements of Eclipse Kepler also apply to JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1. For example, GTK is required as the windowing system on Linux distributions, Win32 on Microsoft Windows operating systems and Cocoa on OS X operating systems. For more information about Eclipse Kepler system requirements see <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/eclipse/development/readme_eclipse_4.3.html"/> on the Eclipse website.
		</para>
		<para>
			The Visual Page Editor and BrowserSim tools have additional Java developer kit requirements and restrictions: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The visual component of the Visual Page Editor, which depends on XULRunner, does not operate in the 64-bit version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio on OS X and Microsoft Windows operating systems. To work around this restriction on 64-bit OS X and Microsoft Windows operating systems, you must install a 32-bit version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio with a 32-bit Java developer kit.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						BrowserSim, which depends on WebKit, requires Apple Safari to be installed on Microsoft Windows operating systems. Only a 32-bit version of Apple Safari is available for Microsoft Windows operating systems. To work around this restriction for 64-bit Microsoft Windows operating systems running 64-bit versions of JBoss Developer Studio, you must set BrowserSim to use a 32-bit JVM by editing the BrowserSim preferences from within the IDE. Note that 32-bit JVM choice is limited to Oracle 32-bit JRE 1.6, JDK 1.6, or JDK 1.7 on Microsoft Windows operating systems because Oracle 32-bit JRE 1.7 is incompatible with Apple Safari.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Computer_Memory" remap="TID_13538">
		<title>Computer Memory</title>
		<para>
			To install and run JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1, the following memory requirements are recommended: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						4 GB RAM
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						1.5 GB of hard disk space
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		<para>
			The minimum memory requirements are 2 GB RAM and 750 MB of hard disk space.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="Compatible_Java_Developer_Kits" remap="TID_13333">
		<title>Compatible Java Developer Kits</title>
		<para>
			JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7.1 requires a Java developer kit of version 1.6 or later. This release of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio is supported on the operating system and Java developer kit combinations listed in the table below.
		</para>
		<table>
			<title>Supported Combinations of Operating Systems and Java Developer Kits</title>
			<tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colwidth="1*"/>
				<colspec colwidth="1*"/>
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Operating System
						</entry>
						<entry>
							Java Developer Kit
						</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6
						</entry>
						<entry>
							OpenJDK 1.6, OpenJDK 1.7, Oracle JDK 1.6 and Oracle JDK 1.7
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Microsoft Windows XP
						</entry>
						<entry>
							Oracle JDK 1.6
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Microsoft Window 7 and Windows 8
						</entry>
						<entry>
							Oracle JDK 1.6 and Oracle JDK 1.7
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							OS X Lion (10.7) and OS X Mountain Lion (10.8)
						</entry>
						<entry>
							Apple JDK 1.6 and Oracle JDK 1.7 (64-bit only)
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Fedora 18 and Fedora 19
						</entry>
						<entry>
							OpenJDK 1.6 and OpenJDK 1.7
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>
							Ubuntu 12.04.2 LTS and Ubuntu 13.04
						</entry>
						<entry>
							OpenJDK 1.6 and OpenJDK 1.7
						</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
		<para>
			Before installing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio you must identify which Java developer kit you have installed. If it is not listed above, you must install a compatible one before proceeding.
		</para>
		<important>
			<para>
				You must use a 32-bit Java developer kit to install a 32-bit version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio and a 64-bit Java developer kit to install a 64-bit version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio.
			</para>
		</important>
		<itemizedlist role="see-also-list">
			<title>See Also:</title>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="appe-Java_Developer_Kits" xrefstyle="see-also"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
</chapter>