<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "JBoss_Developer_Studio_Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Supported_Operating_Systems_and_Architectures" remap="TID_13331">
	<sectioninfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>
				JBDS 7.0.0
			</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</sectioninfo>
	<title>Supported Operating Systems and Architectures</title>
	<para>
		JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 is supported on the operating systems listed in the table below.
	</para>
	<table id="Supported_OS">
		<title>Supported Operating Systems</title>
		<tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
			<colspec colwidth="2*"/>
			<colspec colwidth="1*"/>
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Operating System
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Chip Architecture
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6
					</entry>
					<entry>
						x86, x86_64
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Microsoft Windows XP, Windows 7 and Windows 8
					</entry>
					<entry>
						x86, x86_64
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						OS X Lion (10.7) and OS X Mountain Lion (10.8)
					</entry>
					<entry>
						x86_64
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Fedora 18 and Fedora 19
					</entry>
					<entry>
						x86, x86_64
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Ubuntu 11.10, Ubuntu 12.04 LTS, Ubuntu 12.10 and Ubuntu 13
					</entry>
					<entry>
						x86, x86_64
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
	<para>
		As JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 is based on Eclipse Kepler (4.3), the system requirements of Eclipse Kepler also apply to JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7. For example, GTK is required as the windowing system on Linux distributions, Win32 on Microsoft Windows operating systems and Cocoa on OS X operating systems. For more information about Eclipse system requirements see <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/"/> on the Eclipse website.
	</para>
	<para>
		The Visual Page Editor and BrowserSim tools of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 have additional system requirements and restrictions: 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The visual component of the Visual Page Editor, which depends on XULRunner, does not operate in the 64-bit version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio on OS X and Microsoft Windows operating systems. To work around this restriction, you must install a 32-bit version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio on 64-bit OS X and Microsoft Windows operating systems.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					BrowserSim, which depends on WebKit, requires Apple Safari to be installed on Microsoft Windows operating systems. Only a 32-bit version of Apple Safari is available for Microsoft Windows operating systems. To work around this restriction, you must install a 32-bit version of Apple Safari and a 32-bit version of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio on 32-bit and 64-bit Microsoft Windows operating systems.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
</section>