<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Red_Hat_JBoss_Developer_Studio_Migration_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="chap-Upgrade_from_Previous_Versions_of_JBoss_Developer_Studio">
	<title>Upgrade from Previous Versions of JBoss Developer Studio</title>
	<section id="Back_up_existing_workspaces" remap="TID_13419">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Upgrade Methods</title>
		<para>
			The method for upgrading JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio depends on whether you are using JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio or JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE.
		</para>
		<warning>
			<para>
				Before upgrading, you are advised to back up your workspace. In addition to your project files, your workspace contains meta-data about customized setting and preferences for JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio or Eclipse. To back up your workspace, either copy the workspace directory to a backup location or save it as a compressed file.
			</para>
		</warning>
	</section>
	<section id="Upgrade_JBoss_Developer_Studio" remap="TID_13415">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Upgrade JBoss Developer Studio</title>
		<para>
			It is not possible to upgrade an existing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio installation to JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 because they are based on different versions of Eclipse. For example, JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 6 is based on Eclipse Juno (4.2) but JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 is based on Eclipse Kepler (4.3).
		</para>
		<para>
			To use JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7, you must download and run the universal installer available from the Customer Portal at <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com"/>.
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				You can use different versions of JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio alongside each other by installing them in different directories.
			</para>
		</note>
	</section>
	<section id="Upgrade_JBoss_Developer_Studio_within_Eclipse" remap="TID_13417">
		<sectioninfo>
			<keywordset>
				<keyword>
					JBDS 7.0.0
				</keyword>
			</keywordset>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Upgrade JBoss Developer Studio BYOE</title>
		<para>
			It is not possible to upgrade an existing JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio BYOE to JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 BYOE because they support different versions of Eclipse. For example, JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 6 BYOE supports Eclipse Juno but JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 BYOE supports Eclipse Kepler.
		</para>
		<para>
			To use JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 BYOE, you must upgrade to Eclipse Kepler and install JBoss&nbsp;Developer&nbsp;Studio 7 BYOE from Eclipse Marketplace.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>