<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Customizing BrowserSim</title>

	<section>
		<title>Customizing Overview</title>
	
		<para>The aim of this section is to guide you in customizing BrowserSim:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Make BrowserSim more prominent to use by making it the default browser, by adding its icon to the global toolbar and creating a shortcut key for launching it</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Extend the functionality of BrowserSim by adding or modify the simulated devices it provides</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Customize the default settings of BrowserSim for large simulated devices, for screen captures and for Weinre</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Make BrowserSim the Default Browser</title>
	
		<para><!--A variety of web browsers can be used to view web pages in the IDE.--> You can set BrowserSim to be the default browser used in actions such as <guimenu>Show In</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Web Browser</guimenu> and <guimenu>Run on Server</guimenu>.</para>
		
		<para>To set BrowserSim as the default browser, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Web Browser</guimenu> and click <guimenu>BrowserSim</guimenu>.</para>
		
		<para>Alternatively, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>, expand <guilabel>General</guilabel> and select <guilabel>Web Browser</guilabel>. Select the <guilabel>BrowserSim</guilabel> check box. Click <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <application>Preferences</application> window.</para>

	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Add BrowserSim to the Global Toolbar</title>
	
		<para>The BrowserSim icon is part of the BrowserSim toolbar and, by default, this toolbar is included in the global toolbar of the JBoss perspective. But the BrowserSim icon might not be visible in other perspectives because the icons in the global toolbar change depending on the perspective you are using. As detailed in the procedure below, you can add the BrowserSim toolbar to other perspectives.</para>
		
		<procedure>
			<title>Add BrowserSim to the Global Toolbar in the Current Perspective</title>
			<step><para>Ensure you are using the perspective in which you would like to add the BrowserSim toolbar. If you need to change the perspective, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Open Perspective</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Other</guimenu> and search for the appropriate perspective.</para></step>
			<step><para>Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Customize Perspective</guimenu>.</para></step>
			<step><para>On the <guilabel>Command Groups Availability</guilabel> tab, select the <guilabel>BrowserSim</guilabel> check box to add this command group to the current perspective.</para></step>
			<step><para>On the <guilabel>Tool Bar Visibility</guilabel> tab, ensure the <guilabel>BrowserSim</guilabel> check box is selected as this makes the BrowserSim toolbar visible.</para></step>
			<step><para>Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window. The <guibutton>Run BrowserSim</guibutton> icon is now visible in the global toolbar of the perspective.</para></step>
		</procedure>
		
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Set a Shortcut for the Run BrowserSim Action</title>
		
		<para>If you use BrowserSim frequently but do not want to set it as the default browser, you can set a shortcut for the <guibutton>Run BrowserSim</guibutton> action, as described in the procedure below.</para>

		<procedure>
			<title>Set a Shortcut for BrowserSim</title>
			
			<step><para>Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>, expand <guilabel>General</guilabel> and select <guilabel>Keys</guilabel>.</para></step>
			<step><para>To find the Run BrowserSim action, in the <guilabel>type filter text</guilabel> field enter <command>BrowserSim</command>.</para></step>
			<step><para>In the table, select <guilabel>Run BrowserSim</guilabel>.</para></step>
			<step><para>In the <guilabel>Binding</guilabel> field, type the key combination you want to use as a shortcut. Check the <guilabel>Conflicts</guilabel> table to ensure the key binding you have chosen does not conflict with existing shortcuts.</para></step>
			<step><para>Once a unique key binding is selected, click <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <application>Preferences</application> window.</para></step>
		</procedure>
			
	</section>
			

	<section>
		<title>Add or Modify Devices in BrowserSim</title>
	
		<para>You may wish to preview a web application on a simulated mobile device that is not predefined in BrowserSim. You can add more devices to BrowserSim and modify the existing devices, as detailed below.</para>

		<procedure>
			<title>Add Devices to BrowserSim</title>
			<step><para>Right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>.</para></step>
			<step><para>In the <guilabel>Devices</guilabel> window, click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>.</para></step>
			<step><para>In the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> field, type the name you want to give the device.</para></step>
			<step><para>In the <guilabel>Width</guilabel> and <guilabel>Height</guilabel> fields, type the dimensions of the device window in pixels.</para></step>
			<step><para>In the <guilabel>Pixel Ratio</guilabel> field, type a value for the ratio of CSS pixels to device pixels.</para></step>
			<step><para>In the <guilabel>User Agent</guilabel> field, type the User Agent string of your device. Clearing the <guilabel>User Agent</guilabel> check box results in the default User Agent for the BrowserSim browser being used.</para>
				<note>
					<para>User Agent is a string denoting the device, operating system and browser combination. This string may be used by websites to provide content tailored for devices, operating systems and browsers. Information is widely available on the Internet to assist you in identifying the User Agent associated with a particular device.</para>
				</note></step>
			<step><para>From the <guilabel>Skin</guilabel> list, select the skin to be used or select <guilabel>None</guilabel>.</para></step>
			<step><para>Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to add the new device and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Devices</guilabel> window.</para></step>
		</procedure>

		<para>To modify existing devices in BrowserSim, right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. In the <guilabel>Devices</guilabel> table, select a device and click <guibutton>Edit</guibutton>. Once you have finished editing the fields, click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Devices</guilabel> window.</para>

		<!--<procedure>
			<title>Modify Devices in BrowserSim</title>
			<step><para>Right-click the browser window and click <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>.</para></step>
			<step><para>In the <guilabel>Devices</guilabel> table, select a device and click <guibutton>Edit</guibutton>.</para></step>
			<step><para>Once you have finished editing the fields, click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.</para></step>
			<step><para>Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the <guilabel>Devices</guilabel> window.</para></step>
		</procedure> -->
		
	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Change the Default Behavior when a Device does not Fit the Display</title>
	
		<para>By default, when a device window is too large to fit the display of the system, you are prompted about which action should be taken. Rather than prompting, the default behavior can be set to always truncate or never truncate.</para>
		
		<para>To change the default behavior, right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. Under <guilabel>Truncate the device window when it does not fit display</guilabel>, click <guilabel>Always truncate</guilabel> or <guilabel>Never truncate</guilabel> to change the behavior as appropriate and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window.</para>
	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Change the Default Location for Saved Screen Captures</title>
		
		<para>The <guimenu>Save</guimenu> option for screen captures saves graphics files to a set location. The default location can be changed.</para>
		
		<para>To change the default location, right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. Under <guilabel>Screenshots</guilabel>, in the <guilabel>Location</guilabel> field type the location where you want graphics files to be saved or click <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to navigate to the desired location. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window.</para>
		
	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Change the Default Settings for Weinre</title>
		
		<para>By default, the <guimenu>Weinre</guimenu> option for viewing the source of a web page uses the Weiner server provided by PhoneGap. If you have a different Weiner server available, the default Weinre settings can be changed.</para>
		
		<para>To change the default settings for Weinre, right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. Under <guilabel>Weinre</guilabel>, in the <guilabel>Script URL</guilabel> field type the address of the <filename>.js</filename> file provided by the Weinre server and in the <guilabel>Client URL</guilabel> field type the address of the web page showing the Weinre Inspector interface. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window.</para>
		
	</section>

</section>

