<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Features of BrowserSim</title>

	<section>
	<title>Features Overview</title>
	
		<para>The aim of this section is to guide you in using BrowserSim:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>View local and remote web applications in BrowserSim</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Change the appearance of simulated devices, by rotating them and changing or removing their skins</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Check the look and functionality of web pages in different browsers, such as the default browser or additional synchronized simulated devices</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Generate screen captures of simulated devices and their web pages</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>View the page source of web pages with editors, Firebug Lite and Weinre</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para><remark>[DOCS] Watching JBIDE-13142: open in new widow option will be removed; ERD JBDS70_0028/JBDS-2522 click on any browser makes all others come to top too</remark></para>
		
	</section>

	
	<section>
		<title>View a Web Application on BrowserSim</title>
	
		<para>You can use BrowserSim to view web applications on local file systems or deployed on runtime servers.</para>

		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>To view web applications in local file systems</term>
				<listitem><para>In the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> tab, select a <filename>.html</filename> file and click the <guibutton>Run BrowserSim</guibutton> icon. Alternatively, right-click a <filename>.html</filename> file and click <guimenu>Open With</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>BrowserSim</guimenu>.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>To view deployed web applications</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><remark>[QE]In the <guilabel>Servers</guilabel> tab, expand the server on which the application is deployed. Right-click the application and click <guimenu>Show In</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>BrowserSim</guimenu>. Alternatively, select the application and click the <guibutton>Run BrowserSim</guibutton> icon. If BrowserSim is the IDE browser preferences, you can also right-click the application and click <guimenu>Show In</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Web Browser</guimenu>.</remark></para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		
		<para>BrowserSim employs intelligent loading when selecting which web page to open in the browser window. If a web page is already open in a standard browser window, this is the web page that is loaded in BrowserSim.</para>

	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Manage Web Applications on BrowserSim</title>
	
		<para><remark>[QE, whole section]</remark></para>
	
		<para>BrowserSim provides actions to assist with viewing web applications on its simulated devices.</para>
		
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Open a web link</term>
				<listitem><para>In the browser window, click the web link. The link will open on the simulated device.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>	
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Show or hide the address bar</term>
				<listitem><para>Click the notification bar, where the connectivity, time and battery are displayed, to show or hide the address bar.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>	
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Reload a web page</term>
				<listitem><para>Click the <guilabel>Reload</guilabel> icon at the end of the address bar.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>	
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Stop loading a web page</term>
				<listitem><para>Click the <guilabel>Stop</guilabel> icon at the end of the address bar.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>		
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Close BrowserSim</term>
				<listitem><para>Right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Close</guimenu>. Open BrowserSim windows automatically close when the IDE closes.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>

	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Change the Appearance of a Simulated Device</title>
	
		<para>BrowserSim provides a number of ways to change the appearance of simulated devices. <remark>[QE]Changes made to the appearance of simulated devices are retained by BrowserSim and they are automatically applied when it starts in future.</remark></para>
		
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Rotate the view between portrait and landscape modes</term>
				<listitem><para>Click any corner of the simulated device. Alternatively, right-click the simulated device and click <remark>[QE]<guimenu>Rotate Left</guimenu> or <guimenu>Rotate Right</guimenu></remark>.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Change the simulated device</term>
				<listitem><para>Right-click the simulated device, <remark>[QE]click <guimenu>Skins</guimenu></remark> and select from the listed devices.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Remove or use skins</term>
				<listitem><para>To view a plain browser window without the mobile device skin, right-click the simulated device and clear the <guilabel>Use Skins</guilabel> check box. To reapply the skin, click <guimenu>Devices</guimenu> and select the <guilabel>Use Skins</guilabel> check box.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>

	</section>	

	<section>
		<title>View a Web Page in Different Browsers and Simulated Devices</title>
		
		<para>From within BrowserSim, web pages can be viewed in different browsers and simulated devices.</para>
		
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>View in the default browser of the system</term>
				<listitem><para>Right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Open in default browser</guimenu>. An external browser window opens and displays the web page.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>View simultaneously on synchronized simulated devices</term>
				<listitem><para>Right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Open Synchronized Window</guimenu>. Select from the list of available skins for the additional simulated device. An additional simulated device opens and displays the same web page as that of the synchronized simulated device. Opening a web page in one synchronized simulated device results in the web page opening in all the synchronized simulated devices.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>					
		</variablelist>
		
	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Generate a Screen Capture of a Simulated Device</title>

		<para>BrowserSim provides the ability to generate screen captures of a simulated device and the web pages it shows.</para>
		
		<para>To generate a screen capture of a simulated device, right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>Screenshot</guimenu>. Select the output for the screen capture from the list of options:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para><guimenu>Save</guimenu> to save as a <filename>.png</filename> file in the default location. <remark>[QE]The default location is your home directory.</remark></para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guimenu>Save as</guimenu> to save as a <filename>.png</filename> file in a location you specify.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guimenu>Copy to clipboard</guimenu> to copy the graphic for immediate use.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Activate LiveReload for BrowserSim</title>
		<para><remark>[DOCS]Still need to do this, see JBIDE-13379</remark></para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>View the Source of a Web Page</title>
		
		<para>From within BrowserSim, the source of web pages can be viewed with a variety of applications.</para>
		
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>				
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Open the page source in an editor</term>
				<listitem><para>Right-click the simulated device and click <guimenu>View Page Source</guimenu>. The file containing the page source opens in an editor tab.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Inspect the page source with Firebug Lite</term>
				<listitem><para>Right-click the simulated device and click <remark>[QE]<guimenu>Debug</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Firebug Lite</guimenu>.</remark> The Firebug Lite application is displayed in an external window.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Inspect and edit the page source with Weinre</term>
				<listitem><para>Right-click the simulated device and click <remark>[QE]<guimenu>Debug</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Weinre</guimenu>.</remark> The Weinre Inspector is displayed in an external window. Weinre supports remote debugging, enabling you to debug an application running on a mobile device from your desktop browser.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		
	</section>
</section>

