<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Overview of BrowserSim</title>
	
	<section>
		<title>About BrowserSim</title>
	
		<para>BrowserSim is a mobile web browser simulator. It enables you to view and interact with web pages as they would appear on mobile devices.</para>
		
		<para>BrowserSim consists of an external web browser window. This browser window is different from standard browsers in that it can be transformed to simulate browsers on a variety of mobile devices. The browser window can also be rotated to demonstrate the changes that would occur to a web application as a result of rotating a mobile device. Additionally, BrowserSim provides access to tools for inspecting and editing the source of web pages.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>System Requirements</title>

		<para><phrase condition="jbds">The overall system requirements of JBoss Developer Studio are applicable for BrowserSim and can be viewed in the JBoss Developer Studio Installation Guide at <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com"/> on the Red Hat Customer Portal.</phrase><phrase condition="jbt">The overall system requirements of JBoss Tools are applicable for BrowserSim and can be viewed at <ulink url="https://community.jboss.org/wiki/MatrixOfSupportedPlatformsRuntimesAndTechnologiesInJBossToolsJBDS"/> on the JBoss Tools website.</phrase> But, as reiterated below, there are additional system requirements and restrictions when using BrowserSim on Microsoft Windows operating systems.</para>
	
		<para>BrowserSim depends on WebKit and, consequently, requires Apple Safari to be installed on Microsoft Windows operating systems. Only a 32-bit version of Apple Safari is available for Microsoft Windows operating systems. To work around this restriction for 64-bit Microsoft Windows operating systems, you must set BrowserSim to use a 32-bit JVM when running in 64-bit versions of <phrase condition="jbds">JBoss Developer Studio</phrase><phrase condition="jbt">Eclipse</phrase>. Note that 32-bit JVM choice is limited to Oracle 32-bit JRE 1.6, JDK 1.6, or JDK 1.7 on Microsoft Windows operating systems because Oracle 32-bit JRE 1.7 is incompatible with Apple Safari.</para>
		
		<para>To set BrowserSim to use a 32-bit JVM, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. Expand <guilabel>JBoss Tools</guilabel> and select <guilabel>BrowserSim/CordovaSim</guilabel>. Under <guilabel>Select JRE to run BrowserSim</guilabel>, click <guilabel>Select</guilabel> and from the list select a 32-bit JRE or Java developer kit. Click <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window.</para>

	</section>

</section>

