<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Features of JBoss Central and the JBoss Perspective</title>

	<section>
	<title>Features Overview</title>
	
		<para>The aim of this section is to guide you in using JBoss Central and the JBoss perspective:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>View JBoss Central to access project wizards and information resources</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Install and update software with JBoss Central</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Open the JBoss perspective for easy access to key tabs, menus and toolbars</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Access cheat sheets that assist in project development</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<!--<para><remark>[DOCS] Watching JBIDE-2557: cheat sheets for archetypes; Also cheat sheets missing for quickstarts; JBIDE-14804: uninstall from central</remark></para>-->

	</section>

	
	<section>
		<title>View JBoss Central</title>
		
		<para>The <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab provides resources for getting started and updating software.</para>
		
		<para>To open the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab, click the <guibutton>JBoss Central</guibutton> icon. Alternatively, click <guimenu>Help</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>JBoss Central</guimenu>.</para>

		<para>To maximize the  <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab, double-click the name of the <guibutton>JBoss Central</guibutton> tab. The <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab fills the whole IDE window. Double-click the name of the <guibutton>JBoss Central</guibutton> tab to reduce the size of the tab again. These actions work for all IDE tabs.</para>

	</section>	


	<section>
		<title>Access Project Wizards in JBoss Central</title>

		<para>JBoss Central provides access to wizards for generating projects. There are two types of project wizards available in JBoss Central:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para>The <guilabel>Start from scratch</guilabel> wizards create the same project using different underlying technology, as started in the project name. To view a project summary, hover the cursor over a project wizard. If you do not have the necessary plug-in installed to use a wizard, you will be prompted to install it when you click the wizard. </para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>The <guilabel>Start from a sample</guilabel> wizards create  sample web, mobile, back-end and portal applications.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	
		<para>To create a project from one of the wizards, in the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab select the <guilabel>Getting Started</guilabel> page. Click on one of the links below <guilabel>Start from scratch</guilabel> or <guilabel>Start from a sample</guilabel>. Alternatively, click <guimenu>File</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>New</guimenu> and select a project from the list. A wizard opens to guide you through the process of creating the project.</para>

		<para>Additionally, access is provided to the comprehensive TicketMonster tutorial, part of JBoss Developer Framework, that guides you through developing a complex web application utilizing JBoss technologies from within the IDE. To view the tutorial, in the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab select the <guilabel>Getting Started</guilabel> page and click the <guibutton>Open the Ticket Monster tutorial</guibutton> button. The JBoss Developer Framework website will open in the default browser of the IDE.</para>
	
	</section>
	

	<section>
		<title>Access Information in JBoss Central</title>

		<para>JBoss Central provides easy access to JBoss and developer information. Each of the information sources listed below are web-based and, depending on the web browser preferences you have set for the IDE, clicking on links results in an internal or external browser window opening.</para>
		
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>View JBoss Developer Studio website</term>
				<listitem><para>In the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab, click the <guibutton>JBoss Developer Studio Home</guibutton> icon.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>View the latest JBoss developments</term>
				<listitem><para>In the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab, select the <guilabel>Getting Started</guilabel> page and click the links under <guilabel>JBoss Buzz</guilabel>. To see previews of the blog posts, hover the cursor over these links. To view a complete list of JBoss blog posts, click the <guibutton>JBoss Buzz</guibutton> button. JBoss blog posts are available to follow as RSS feeds or with Twitter. To review these options, click the <guibutton>News</guibutton> or <guibutton>Twitter</guibutton> icons.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>					
			<varlistentry>
				<term>View JBoss developer information sources</term>
				<listitem><para>In the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab, select the <guilabel>Getting Started</guilabel> page and click the links under <guilabel>Other resources</guilabel>. These links provide access to videos, documentation and forums.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Search JBoss Community website</term>
				<listitem><para>In the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab, click the arrow next to the search box and select <guilabel>Search JBoss Community</guilabel>. In the search field, enter the search terms.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>					
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Search Red Hat Customer Portal website</term>
				<listitem><para>In the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab, click the arrow next to the search box and select <guilabel>Search Red Hat Customer Portal</guilabel>. In the search field, enter the search terms.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>	
		</variablelist>
		
	</section>


	<!-- Not this release 
	<section>
		<title>Work offline with JBoss Central</title>
		
		<para><remark>[DOCS] Still to do</remark></para>
		
		<para><remark>JBDS-2556/2552/2543: offline usage of JBoss central, examples/archetypes/;</remark></para>
		
	</section> -->


	<section>
		<title>Update Software in JBoss Central</title>
		
		<para>JBoss Central enables you to install and update a range of IDE plug-ins. The available plug-ins comprise JBoss and third party plug-ins that have been specifically tested for use with the IDE. These plug-ins include ones for web and mobile development, source control management, testing and Maven.</para> 
		
		<para>For all actions listed below, open the <guilabel>JBoss Central</guilabel> tab and select the <guilabel>Software/Update</guilabel> page.</para>
		
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>				
			<varlistentry>
				<term>View available software</term>
				<listitem><para>The available software is listed in the table. To refresh the list of available plug-ins, click the <guibutton>Refresh</guibutton> icon.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>	
			<varlistentry>
				<term>View installed plug-ins</term>
				<listitem><para>Select the <guilabel>Show Installed</guilabel> check box. The installed plug-ins are listed in the table as disabled.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Install available software</term>
				<listitem><para>In the <guilabel>Find</guilabel> field, type the name of the software or scroll through the list to locate it. Select the check box corresponding to the software you want to install and click <guibutton>Install</guibutton> or click the <guibutton>Install</guibutton> icon.</para> 
				<para>In the <application>Install</application> wizard, ensure the check boxes are selected for the software you want to install and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>. Review the details of the items listed for install and click <guibutton>Next</guibutton>. After reading and agreeing to the licenses, click <guilabel>I accept the terms of the license agreements</guilabel> and click <guibutton>Finish</guibutton>. The <guilabel>Installing Software</guilabel> window opens and reports the progress of the installation.</para> 
				<para>During the installation process you may receive warnings about installing unsigned content. If this is the case, check the details of the content and if satisfied click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to continue with the installation. Once installing is complete, you are prompted to restart the IDE. Click <guibutton>Yes</guibutton> to restart now and <guibutton>No</guibutton> if you need to save any unsaved changes to open projects. Note that changes do not take effect until the IDE is restarted.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>	
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Check for software updates</term>
				<listitem><para>Click the <guibutton>Check for Updates</guibutton> icon. The <guilabel>Contacting Software Sites</guilabel> window opens and reports the progress of checking. Once checking is complete, a prompt informs you of any new software found. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the prompt.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>		
		
	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Open the JBoss Perspective</title>
		
		<para>The JBoss perspective provides a default set of tabs, menus and toolbars to assist with common tasks associated with developing applications that use JBoss technologies.</para>
		
		<para>To open the JBoss perspective, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Open Perspective</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Other</guimenu>. From the list of available perspectives, select <guilabel>JBoss</guilabel> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>. The tabs associated with the JBoss perspective open and menus and toolbars change as appropriate.</para>

	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Manage JBoss Perspective</title>
		
		<para>There are a number of actions provided by the IDE for managing perspectives, including the JBoss perspective.</para>
			
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Reset the JBoss perspective</term>
				<listitem><para>You may want to reset the JBoss perspective to its default settings after opening and closing tabs. Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Reset Perspective</guimenu>. At the prompt asking if you want to reset the current JBoss perspective to its default settings, click <guibutton>Yes</guibutton>.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Switch to the JBoss perspective</term>
				<listitem><para>You can have multiple perspectives open at one time. To switch to the JBoss perspective, click the <guibutton>JBoss</guibutton> button. Alternatively, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Navigation</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Next Perspective</guimenu> or press <keycap>Ctrl+F8</keycap> and repeat until the JBoss perspective is the current perspective.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>									
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Close the JBoss perspective</term>
				<listitem><para>Click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Close Perspective</guimenu>.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>	
		</variablelist>
		
	</section>


	<section>
		<title>View Cheat Sheets</title>

		<para>Typically, cheat sheets contain detailed information about projects, with step by step guidance and explanations for how to create and deploy applications. JBoss Central and the JBoss perspective provide actions to make the cheat sheets that accompany projects easier to access and view<!--, including the cheat sheets that accompany the <guilabel>Start from scratch</guilabel> and <guilabel>Start from a sample</guilabel> projects available in JBoss Central. -->.</para>

		<!-- JBDS-2557: cheat sheets on archetypes and quickstarts -->
		<!-- <para>When you create a new project with an accompanying cheat sheet, the <guilabel>Cheat Sheets</guilabel> tab automatically opens and displays the cheat sheet.</para> -->

		<para>A cheat sheet contained in a project is automatically opened in the <guilabel>Cheat Sheets</guilabel> tab when the project is imported into the workspace with <guimenu>File</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Import</guimenu>.</para>

		<para>To open a cheat sheet manually, in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> tab right-click the project name or a cheat sheet file and click <guimenu>Show In</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Cheat Sheets</guimenu>. Alternatively, click <guimenu>Help</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Cheat Sheets</guimenu>, click <guilabel>Select a cheat sheet from a file</guilabel> and type the location of the file in the field or click <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to navigate to the file. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window. The cheat sheet opens in the <guilabel>Cheat Sheets</guilabel> tab.</para>
		
		<note><para>If the cheat sheet file name begins with dot, it may not be automatically visible in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> tab. To change the viewing preferences of the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> tab, click the <guibutton>View Menu</guibutton> icon and click <guimenu>Customize View</guimenu>. In the <guilabel>Filters</guilabel> tab, clear the <guilabel>.* resources</guilabel> check box and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.</para></note>
		
		<!-- API for developing cheat sheets available to all -->
		
	</section>

</section>

