<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Features of Forge Tools</title>

	<section>
	<title>Features Overview</title>
	
		<para>The aim of this section is to guide you in using Forge Tools:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>View and manage the Forge Console tab, from which the Forge command line is accessible</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Start and stop the Forge runtime server in order to access the command line</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Navigate to project resources in the Forge command line</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Understand how Forge commands affect the IDE through background actions, such as expanding directories in explorer tabs and opening files in editors</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Use wizards for accomplishing common Forge commands as an alternative to the Forge command line</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<!--<para><remark>[DOCS] Watching JBIDE-13486: open a cheat sheet after starting Forge; JBIDE-13573: add debug/run button or preferences action in console; JBIDE-13192: pick-up automatically executed after new-project command; JBIDE-13194: ask user to restart forge after changing VM arguments or changing debug mode; JBIDE-14615: set VERBOSE command opens Error Log tab; JBIDE-12443: Add forge tab to JBoss perspective</remark></para> -->

	</section>

	
	<section>
		<title>Manage the Forge Console</title>
	
		<para>A key element for working with Forge is the Forge command line. In order to view this, you need to open the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab.</para>

		<para>To open the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Show View</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Other</guimenu>. Expand <guilabel>Forge</guilabel>, select <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>. Alternatively, press <keycap>Ctrl+4</keycap>, at which you are prompted whether you also want to start Forge. Irrespective of your response to starting Forge, the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab opens.</para>

	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Manage the Forge Runtime Server</title>
		
		<para>You must start a Forge runtime server in order to access the Forge command line. Forge Tools provides actions for starting and managing the Forge runtime server.</para>
		
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Start Forge</term>
				<listitem><para>In the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab, click the <guibutton>Start the default Forge runtime</guibutton> icon. Alternatively, press <keycap>Ctrl+4</keycap> and at the prompt asking if you want to start Forge, click <guibutton>Yes</guibutton>. A progress bar in the IDE window and text in the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab indicate the starting status of the Forge runtime server.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Run Forge in the background</term>
				<listitem><para>With a running instance of Forge, in the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab click the <guibutton>Close tab</guibutton> icon. Despite the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab not being open, Forge will continue to run in the background. Reopen the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab to access the same Forge command line, identifiable by the existing command line output.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Stop Forge</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>In the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab, click the <guibutton>Stop the running Forge runtime</guibutton> icon. Alternatively, on the Forge command line, enter <command>exit</command>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		
	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Navigate to Project Resources on the Forge Command Line</title>

		<para>Forge Tools enables you to efficiently navigate to project resources, such as directories and files, on the Forge command line.</para>

		<para>To navigate to a project resource on the Forge command line, in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> tab right-click any project resource and click <guimenu>Show In</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Forge Console</guimenu>. If the Forge runtime server is not started, you are prompted to start it. At the prompt, click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>. Alternatively, in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> tab, select a project resource and click the <guibutton>Go to Selection</guibutton> icon in the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel> tab.</para>
		
		<para>Both of these actions result in the Forge command line automatically executing the <command>pick-up</command> command for the project resource. Following this, the command line navigates to the project resource, the command prompt indicates the selected resource, and the resource opens in an editor if it is a file.</para>
				
	</section>


	<section>
		<title>Background Actions Invoked by Forge Commands</title>
		
		<para>Forge Tools invokes background actions in the IDE in response to commands issued on the command line in the <guilabel>Forge Console</guilabel>. For example, if you create a project file or directory on the Forge command line, the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> tab is automatically refreshed to show the newly created project resource. A list of Forge commands that result in additional background actions is given below.</para>
	
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<!--JBIDE-14615: RFE<varlistentry>
				<term><command>set VERBOSE true</command></term>
				<listitem><para>The command results in exceptions being recorded in the IDE error log. To open the <guilabel>Error Log</guilabel> tab, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guilabel>Show View</guilabel>&rarr;<guimenu>Other</guimenu> and expand <guilabel>General</guilabel>. Click <guilabel>Error Log</guilabel> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry> -->
			<varlistentry>
				<term><command>cd</command></term>
				<listitem><para>The command navigates to the project directory and selects it in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> and <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel> tabs.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><command>pick-up</command></term>
				<listitem><para>The command navigates to the project resource and in the case that the resource is a file it is opened in an editor within the IDE. The project resource is selected and expanded in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> and <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel> tabs. If the resource resides outside the workspace, it is selected and expanded in the <guilabel>Remote Systems Explorer</guilabel> tab, providing this is installed.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><command>open</command></term>
				<listitem><para>The command opens a file in an editor within the IDE. The project resource is selected and expanded in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> and <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel> tabs. If the resource resides outside the workspace, it is selected and expanded in the <guilabel>Remote Systems Explorer</guilabel> tab, providing this is installed.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><command>new-project</command></term>
				<listitem><para>The command creates a new project. The project is automatically imported into the workspace and it is visible in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> and <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel> tabs.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><command>persistence setup</command></term>
				<listitem><para>The command creates a <filename>persistence.xml</filename> file. This file is selected in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> and <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel> tabs and it is automatically opened in an editor within the IDE.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><command>entity</command></term>
				<listitem><para>The command creates a new entity and associated Java file. This file is selected in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> and <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel> tabs and it is automatically opened in the Java editor within the IDE.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><command>field</command></term>
				<listitem><para>The command creates a new field for an entity. The Java file associated with the entity is selected in the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> and <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel> tabs and it is automatically opened in an editor within the IDE and the field selected. The field is also selected in the <guilabel>Outline</guilabel> tab.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>			
		</variablelist>	
	
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Access a List of Forge Commands</title>
		
		<para>Forge Tools provides access to a readily available list of Forge commands. Additionally, the commands can be easily inserted in to the Forge command line, as detailed below.</para>
		
		<para>To view the list of Forge commands, with a running instance of Forge, press <keycap>Ctrl+4</keycap>. To insert one of the commands in to the Forge command line, in the pop-up window expand the command groups and double-click a command.</para>
		
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Use Forge Wizards</title>

		<para>You may prefer to work with wizards rather than the command line. Forge Tools provides wizards for some of the most used Forge commands, in addition to supporting command line functionality. There are three wizards currently available relating to entities, as detailed below.</para>
		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Entities from Tables</term>
				<listitem><para>This wizard generates entities from an existing database. There are options for creating a new project if one does not already exist and browsing for the driver.jar and driver classes.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>REST Endpoints from Entities</term>
				<listitem><para>This wizard generates REST endpoint for entities.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Scaffold UI from Entities</term>
				<listitem><para>This wizard generates the necessary scaffolding for you to use JPA entities in your project. There are options for JavaServer Faces and AngularJS implementations, with the wizard creating the associated pages and Java backing beans.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>			
		</variablelist>	
		
		<para>To open a Forge Tools wizard, click <guimenu>File</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>New</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Other</guimenu> and expand <guilabel>JBoss Tools</guilabel>&rarr;<guilabel>Forge</guilabel>. Select one of the listed wizards, click <guibutton>Next</guibutton> and follow the instructions. If Forge is not already started, this automatically occurs.</para>
		

					
	</section>
	
</section>

