<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Customizing Mobile Web Tools</title>

	<section>
		<title>Customizing Overview</title>
	
		<para>The aim of this section is to guide you in customizing Mobile Web Tools:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Customize the HTML5 jQuery Mobile templates available in the IDE</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

	</section>

	
	<section>
		<title>Customize jQuery Mobile File Templates</title>

		<para>The <guilabel>HTML5 jQuery Mobile Page</guilabel> template for new HTML files is provided by Mobile Tools. You can customize this template and add more jQuery Mobile templates to the IDE.</para>
	
		<para>To customize the jQuery Mobile templates available in the IDE, click <guimenu>Window</guimenu>&rarr;<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>. Expand <guilabel>Web</guilabel>&rarr;<guilabel>HTML Files</guilabel>&rarr;<guilabel>Editor</guilabel> and select <guilabel>Templates</guilabel>. There are a number of available actions:</para>

		<variablelist>
			<title></title>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Add a template</term>
				<listitem><para>There are several options for adding templates:
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>To create a new template, click <guibutton>New</guibutton>. In the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Description</guilabel> fields, type a name and description of the template, respectively. In the <guilabel>Pattern</guilabel> field, type the code for the template. From the <guilabel>Context</guilabel> list, select the instance in which the IDE should make the template available. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>To restore all templates that have been deleted, click <guibutton>Restore</guibutton>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>To load an existing template into the IDE, click <guibutton>Import</guibutton> and select the file. The file must be an XML file, with appropriate file headers and the HTML5 and jQuery Mobile content written in XML syntax and contained between XML <command>template</command> and <command>templates</command> tags.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Edit a template</term>
				<listitem><para>From the table, select a template and click <guibutton>Edit</guibutton>. You can modify the name, description, code content and context in which the IDE makes the template available. Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to close the window.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>		
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Remove a template</term>
				<listitem><para>From the table, select a template and click <guibutton>Remove</guibutton>. </para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>				

	</section>

</section>

