<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Overview of LiveReload Tools</title>
	
	<section>
		<title>About LiveReload</title>
	
		<para>LiveReload is an open source tool that refreshes web pages open in browsers as their source is edited. Immediate and automatic web page refreshing, without the need to manually refresh, simplifies the workflow of web developers.</para>
		
		<para>LiveReload consists of server-side and client-side components. The server-side application monitors the source and sends notifications as the source is changed. On the client-side, a JavaScript snippet receives the notifications and invokes the browser to refresh the web page. The server-side and client-side components communicate using the WebSocket protocol, which allows the server-side application to send notifications to the client-side JavaScript snippet.</para>
		
		<para>The JavaScript snippet can be installed and activated using a LiveReload browser extension. Alternatively, it can be inserted manually in the HTML pages. Depending upon the changes to the source, the web page is either reloaded or the browser updated instantly without reloading.</para>
		
		<para>The LiveReload application is available for OS X and Microsoft Window operating systems and through a third-party provider for Linux-based operating systems. LiveReload browser extensions are available for Safari, Chrome and Firefox.</para>

	</section>

	
	<section>
		<title>About LiveReload Tools</title>
	
		<para>LiveReload Tools is tooling that implements LiveReload in the IDE. It enables you to take advantage of LiveReload browser refreshing while editing files within the IDE. The capabilities of LiveReload Tools also removes the need to install the LiveReload standalone application or browser extensions.</para>

		<para>LiveReload Tools is the implementation of the LiveReload server-side component, which listens to the IDE for resource changes and sends notifications for refreshes as appropriate. The server can also be configured to inject the livereload.js JavaScript snippet into the source code, which removes the need to install LiveReload browser extensions.</para>
		
		<para>Unique features of LiveReload tools include LiveReload for both workspace and deployed resources due to the use of HTTP protocol for all resources and LiveReload on external devices with access and ease of use for remote connections to LiveReload servers. The LiveReload server can also be used in conjunction with BrowserSim, extending LiveReload to simulated devices.</para>
		
	</section>

</section>

