<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section>
	<title>Overview of OpenShift Tools</title>

	<section>
		<title>About OpenShift</title>
		
		<para>OpenShift is Red Hat's Platform as a Service (PaaS) for applications. It consists of an application platform in the cloud, enabling you to build, test and run applications in a cloud architecture. OpenShift provides disk space, CPU resources, network connectivity, and a runtime environment.</para>

		<para>OpenShift has a number of key features to assist you in developing and deploying applications:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Unique domain names, or namespaces, support the hosting of your applications. A user account provides you with access to the domain, the latter having the potential to be associated with multiple applications.</para></listitem>
			
			<listitem><para>Numerous cartridges give you access to popular language, database and management frameworks. OpenShift can also be customized, allowing you to add APIs of your choice.</para></listitem>
			
			<listitem><para>Gears provide RAM and disk space for your applications and cartridges. OpenShift currently provides two gear sizes:
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>Small - 512MB of RAM, 100MB of swap space, and 1GB of disk space</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Medium - 1GB of RAM, 100MB of swap space, and 1GB of disk space</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			You can use up to three small gears as part of FreeShift, a free OpenShift user account, and extend to more gears and bigger gears with OpenShift Enterprise. OpenShift offers flexibility by letting you choose the number of gears to assign to your application.</para></listitem>
			
			<listitem><para><remark>[QE] Built-in</remark> administrative and stack management frees you up to focus on code development. OpenShift manages the intricate details of deploying your application to the stack and interfacing with middleware technologies for you.</para></listitem>
			
			<listitem><para>Automatic or manual scaling of the resources supporting your applications ensure that application performance does not suffer as usage increases. OpenShift can create additional instances of your application and enable clustering.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>OpenShift can be accessed via the web interface at <ulink url="https://www.openshift.com/"/> on the OpenShift website or via the OpenShift command line interface.</para>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>About OpenShift Tools</title>
		
		<para>OpenShift Tools is tooling available within the IDE for OpenShift. It provides an alternative way of accessing OpenShift and managing the development of applications deployed there.</para>

		<para>OpenShift Tools consists of a set of wizards and actions, which together provide core functionality for developing OpenShift applications:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para>The tools prepare you for working with OpenShift, by assisting you to create OpenShift user accounts and domains.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>OpenShift Tools assists you with the essential tasks of setting up your system and the IDE for OpenShift interaction, such as creating connections and generating and uploading SSH keys.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>When creating and developing OpenShift applications, OpenShift Tools provides wizards for creating new and importing existing OpenShift applications.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>A variety of actions are available for managing deployed applications, for tasks such as restarting applications, uploading changes to applications, viewing OpenShift server output, and deleting applications.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		 </para>
	
	</section>

</section>

